Marcin Ciunelis

Experienced Ruby (on Rails) programmer

phone.+34 684 149 013

blog: http://martinciu.com

location: Barcelona, Spain

email: marcin.ciunelis@gmail.com

github: https://github.com/martinciu

Summary

I am a web developer with more than 10 years of professional experience in designing, development and maintaining various internet applications. I like to deliver simple, maintainable and well designed software. I don't believe in silver bullet solutions. I love experimenting, learning from mistakes and iterating over a software to get closer to the perfect code. Refactoring is my hobby.

Skills

I have professional experience with technologies including:

Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, PostgreSql, Elasticsearch, MongoDB, Redis, Javascript, Coffescript, jQuery, Haml, Backbone, PhoneGap, Capistrano, Nginx, haproxy, AWS, Chef

Technologies that I used in my hobby projects:

Objective-C & Swift on iOs & OS X apps, Node.js, Vagrant, GithubAPI, CoreData, RestKit

Open Source Contributions

Errbit, contributor

The open source error catcher that's Airbrake API compliant

I worked on performance optimization, errors matching improvements and refactoring

https://github.com/errbit/errbit

nullobject, creator

Null Object Design Pattern Ruby implementation https://github.com/martinciu/nullobject

thumbs, creator

Image server proxy that resizes & caches images on the fly https://github.com/martinciu/thumbs

fuubar-cucumber, creator

Cucumber progress bar formatter https://github.com/martinciu/fuubar-cucumber

tire, contributor

A rich Ruby API and DSL for the Elasticsearch search engine I've added support for script fields, field boost and lazy load attributes https://github.com/karmi/retire

Lungo.js, contributor

A HTML5 framework for your mobile applications. I've added support for views loaded by AJAX https://github.com/tapquo/Lungo.js

Work Experience

Software Engineer, jobandtalent.com, Warsaw/Barcelona; 2012 - present

jobandtalent is Europe's first Social Media Recruitment Platform. I was working on:

- API & documentation used by MobileWeb, iOs & Android clients
- Mobile Web version single page app using Backbone and Lungo.js
- extracted two micro services from the platform
- · refactor messy javascript to backbone views and models
- PhoneGap mobile app using Backbone, Coffeescript deployed to App Store, Google
- 3rd party services integration for push notifications, sms, geo service, genderize
- payment gateway integrations PayU Latam, Stripe
- Facebook & LinkedIn integrations & profile imports
- migrate search engine to Elasticsearch setup ES cluster & tweaking client gem
- new features & bug fixes
- whole platform rewrite from Rails 2 to Rails 3

email: marcin.ciunelis@gmail.com **blog**: http://martinciu.com github: https://github.com/martinciu

Software Engineer & Co-founder, zubibu.com, Gdansk, Poland; 2010 - 2011

Zubibu was a SaaS m-commerce solution for online retailers. I was responsible for all backend architecture, and programming, public REST API and documentation. We were scraping hundreds of e-shops and/or their XML data feed processing millions of items on daily basics. Technologies used include: Ruby on Rails 3.1, MongoDB, Redis, Solr, Amzon EC2, S3, Cloudfront, Resque. It is no longer maintained

Software Engineer, G-Force Web Management Polska; Gdansk, Poland; 2006-2009

Responsible for developing custom systems for clients - CRMs, CMSes and ecommerce solutions. Technologies used: Ruby on Rails, PHP5, MySql, PostgreSql.

Software Engineer, G-Forces Web Management Ltd; Maidstone, United Kingdom; 2005 - 2006

G-Forces is a major web development company from Kent, UK specialized in automotive and e-commerce software. I was responsible for developing custom systems for clients -CRMs, CMSes and e-commerce solutions. Technologies used: PHP5, MySql, PostgreSql.

Freelance PHP developer, self-employed; Poland; 2004 - 2005

I worked with several clients on custom CRMs systems and websites.

Internet Specialist/PHP developer, Troll Sp. z o.o.; Sopot, Poland; 2002 - 2004

Troll is a major clothing company in Poland. I was responsible for all company presence in the Internet - managing website, coordinating offline experience with online, marketing campaigns etc. I also worked on several internal system for managing warehouse, ecommerce site and B2B solution.

Education

Gdansk University of Technology, Poland; 3 of 5 years completed, 2000 - 2003

Faculty of Electronics, Telecommunications and Informatics

phone.+34 684 149 013

location: Barcelona, Spain

Achievements

Node Knockout 2011

Created PostCatcher - the HTTP POST requests testing application. Hosted tool for testing and debugging WebHooks. It took 5th place in the Solo category. Technologies used Node.js, Coffescript, Express, Pusher, MongoDB, jQuery. Because it is starting to be popular recently I've started to rewrite it with Rails4 and Ember.js http://postcatcher.in/

Rails Rumble 2010

Participated in RailsRumble 2010. Created tool for monitoring opinions about brands on twitter. It is no longer maintained.

phone.+34 684 149 013
email: marcin.ciunelis@gmail.com
blog: http://martinciu.com
github: https://github.com/martinciu

location: Barcelona, Spain

Languages

- English professional working proficiency
- Spanish beginner
- Polish mother tongue

Interests

Sports

Running (competitions), Mountain Biking (competitions), swimming